Finding aid to the Margaret Mahoney papers SSC.MS.00230
Sophia Smith Collection
- Correspondence, 1932-2011; 2; 7.5 linear feet (18 boxes)
  - Personal correspondence, Christmas cards, lists, incoming, outgoing, 1994-2006 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Personal correspondence, Condolences on Nell Savage Mahoney's death, Feb-Mar 1986 (Box 19, Folder 7-12)
  - Personal correspondence, Get Well wishes, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Personal correspondence, Housekeepers, 1985-1996 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Personal correspondence, Howland Sargeant's death, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Professional correspondence, General, A-Z, 1992-1998 (Box 19, Folder 16-19, Box 20, Folder 1-19, Box 21, Folder 1-18, Box 22, Folder 1-16)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 17-19)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 1-10)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 1-14)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 1-18)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 1-18)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 1-23)
  - Outgoing professional correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1997-2007 (Box 29, Folder 1-17)
- Employment, 1944-2007; 3; 4.25 linear feet (10 boxes)
  This series chronicles Margaret's professional life and is arranged alphabetically by employer name. Margaret's professional journey is illustrated throughout: from government service; her work with the United States War Department in 1944; working to support UNESCO in the State Department; arts funding at Carnegie Corporation; healthcare philanthropy at Carnegie, The Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (RWJF), and the Commonwealth Fund; starting her own company, MEM Associates, Inc., at an age when most of her peers retired; and working with Healthy Steps, Inc., on early childhood education in 2005-2007.
  The Employment series also includes lectures and readings taught by Margaret in her Princeton course "Medicine in Modern America," from 1975-1979.
  Throughout the collection, Margaret Mahoney occasionally wrote notes "to the archives" about her papers and their significance to her. One such note can be found in the Lutheran Medical Center folder of the Employment series.
  - Carnegie Corporation, General, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie Corporation, American Medical Computer and Electronic Network, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Arts, 1961-1974 (Box 29, Folder 20-22)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Associated Councils of the Arts, 1965-1974 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Corporation, "Carnegie Corp. potpourri", 1967-1981 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Clippings, 1954-1962 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Dunfermline gathering, correspondence, planning material, speeches, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 4-7)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Memoranda, 1968-1972 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Oral History, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Corporation, "Random items from Carnegie Corp. days,", 1961-1967 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Studio Watts Workshop, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Kenneth Winter, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Grants docket list, 1969-1980 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Airlie Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, American Medical Association, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, American Sociological Association, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Association of American Medical Colleges, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Beth Israel Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Children's Hospital Medical Center, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Columbia University, 1971 (Box 30, Box 21)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Duke University Medical Center, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Duke, Johns Hopkins, McGill and Standford Universities: Clinical Scholars, 1968-1979 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Florida University, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Genesse Hospital, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, George Washington University, 1970-1972 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Harvard University, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, Health Resources Institute, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant proposals and evaluations, John Hopkins University School of Medicine, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Lutheran Medical Center, 1969-1989 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Meharry Medical College, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Montfiore Hospital, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, National Academy of Sciences, 1969-1972 (Box 31, Folder 9-11)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, National Committee for Careers in the Medical Laboratory, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, New York University Medical Center, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 13-15)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, People's Medical Center, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Student American Medical Association Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Sun Valley Forum on National Health, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, University of California, San Francisco, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, University of Colorado, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, University of Michigan, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, University of Nevada at Reno, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, University of Tennessee, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Welfare Island Development Corporation, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Proposals and evaluations, Youth Project, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Congressional Inquiry, 1983-1984 (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Commonwealth agreement, 1979-2001 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Commonwealth appointment press coverage, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Commonwealth Fund: An Historical Sketch to 1947, approximately 1947 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Directories, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Gifts, 1986-1994 (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Harkness House at 100, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Harkness House Paul Stewart catalog, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Healthy Steps, 1995-2002 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Management and leadership, 1981-1990 (Box 32, Folder 13-19)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Medal, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Publication of "For the Welfare of Mankind,", 1986 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Howland H. Sargeant fund, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Doris Schawartz manuscript on health for aged, 1984-1985 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Rebekah Harkness, 1974-1983 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Mentoring, 1987-1989 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Property Tax, 1982-1984 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, General pediatrics academic development program, 13-14 Sep 1979 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Meeting on the Implementation of Recommendations of Select Panel for Promotion of Child Health, 16 Apr 1981 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Macy Conference on Minorities in Medicine, 19-20 Nov 1981 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Harvard University School of Public Health meeting on the Allocation of Medical Care Resources to Improve the Health of the Public, 22 Dec 1981 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Columbia Seminars at Harkness House, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Foundation Consortium meeting, Meharry Medical College, 2 Jun 1982 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Meeting on the effect of removal of the real property tax exemption on charitable organizations in NYC, 7 Jun 1982 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Ballynahinch Leadership Conference, Aug 1982 (Box 33, Folder 15-18)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Conference on New York State Social Welfare Policy, 1-2 Oct 1982 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Revson Urban Fellows meeting, Columbia University, 23 Nov 1982 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, General American Investors Co., Inc. staff conference, 23 Nov 1982 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Committee on Issues Reducing Dependency, Dec 1982 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Commonwealth Fund Forum, 23-26 May 1983 (Box 33, Folder 23-24)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Congressman Green meeting, 17 Jun 1983 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Setting Municipal Priorities, 2-3 Dec 1983 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Lewis Thomas dinner, 7 Dec 1983 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Academic Health Centers consultative group, Princeton Club, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Duke Private Sector conference, 1983-1985 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, New York Public Library, "In Celebration of Learning", 24 May 1984 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, MIT Symposium honoring Professor Richard Beckhard, 12 Apr 1984 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, American Board of Medical Specialties conference, "Impact of the Certification Process on Graduate Medical Education,", 23 Feb 1985 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, National Conference on Health Care for the Poor, Meharry Medical College, 7-8 Oct 1985 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, John Parrish luncheon, 15 Mar 1987 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, New York Landmarks Conservancy, 13 Oct 1987 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Forum, "Using the City's Health Care Resources Effectively", 29 Oct 1987 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, 150th Anniversary Conference, Rockefeller Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, Oral History focus group, 25 Feb 1991 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth Foundation, Events, The Commonwealth Fund 80th Anniversary VHS Video, 9 Nov 1998; 13:51 min, VHS (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - MEM Associates, Center for Disease Control Foundation, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 12-18)
  - MEM Associates Foundation Inquiry, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 19-22)
  - Healthy Steps, general, book material, 2005-2007 (Box 34, Folder 23-24)
  - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 35, Folder 1-5)
  - Organizational chart of MacArthur Foundation Florida real estate interests, approximately 1924-2012; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Medical University of South Carolina, 1997-1998 (Box 35, Folder 6-11)
  - The Open Society Institute, 1996-1999 (Box 35, Folder 12-17)
  - The Science Coalition, 1995-1997 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Princeton University, Course, "Medicine in Modern America,", 1975-1979 (Box 36, Folder 1-9)
  - Princeton University, Course, "Medicine in Modern America,", 1975-1979 (Box 37, Folder 1-9)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, General, 1972-1980 (Box 37, Folder 10-11)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, Child care papers by Margaret Mahoney, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, Clinical scholars, 1981-1988 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, General, 1949-1985 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Application, June 1947 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Employment record, 1947-1953 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, News clippings, 1950-1954 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, General, 1950-1952 (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, International Conference on the Arts, 1950-1952 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, Libraries, 1950-1952 (Box 38, Folder 9-10)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, Museums, 1950-1955 (Box 38, Folder 11-12)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, Music, 1950-1952 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, Preservation, 1950-1953 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Communiques, Visual arts, 1950-1954 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Publications, General, 1946-1955 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Publications, International Theatre Month, 1951-1953 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Publications, Report of first meeting, 1946 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Travel, General, 1949-1952 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Travel, General, Dept. of State Travel Vouchers, 1953-1954 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - United States National Commission for UNESCO, Travel, Trip to Mexico, D.F., 1947 (Box 39, Folder 2-3)
  - United States War Department, 1944-1945 (Box 39, Folder 4)
- Organizations, 1947-2010; 4; 5 linear feet (12 boxes)
  This series is divided into two sub-series: Professional and Social.
  The Professional sub-series ranges from 1969-1997 and is arranged alphabetically. It focuses on the numerous philanthropic or non-profit organizations that Mahoney advised, either formally as a member of the board of directors, or informally. The scope of Margaret's official involvements can be found in her rsums in the first folder of Series 1. Biographical material.
  The Social sub-series is arranged alphabetically. It comprises a much smaller portion of this series and documents the social clubs that Margaret belonged to from 1947-2010.
  - Professional Directories, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 5-7)
  - Professional committees turn down, 1978-1985 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Aitken Neuroscience Center, 1996-1998 (Box 39, Folder 9-17)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1983-1984 (Box 39, Folder 18-19)
  - American Board of Internal Medicine, 1970-1980 (Box 39, Folder 20-23)
  - American Council on Education, 1979-1981 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - American Public Health Association, 1985-1987 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - American Research Institute for the Arts (ARIA), 1976-1979 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - American Stock Exchange, Board of Governors & Nomination Committee, 1982-1990 (Box 40, Folder 4-10)
  - Arthur Ashe Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 40, Folder 11-12)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 13-14)
  - Brandeis University, Florence Heller Graduate School for Advances Studies in Social Welfare Board of Overseers, 1982-1985 (Box 40, Folder 15-17)
  - Children's Interest Group of Foundations, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 18-19)
  - Columbia UP, 1994-1995 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Columbia University seminar on Philanthropy, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Commonwealth award in science (Sigma Xi), 1983 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Cost of Living Council: Health Industry advisory Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 1-5)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1984-1985 (Box 41, Folder 6-8)
  - Council on Foundations, 1981-1989 (Box 41, Folder 8-26)
  - Council on Foundations, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 1-16)
  - Dermatology Foundation, 1974-1980 (Box 42, Folder 17-18)
  - Dole Foundation for Employment of Persons with Disabilities, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 19-22)
  - Dole Foundation for Employment of Persons with Disabilities, 1986-1998 (Box 43, Folder 1-11)
  - Duke University Council on Aging and Human Development, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Financial Women's Association of New York, 1982-1986 (Box 43, Folder 13-15)
  - The Foundation Center, 1977-1983 (Box 43, Folder 16-21)
  - Foundation Executives Group, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 22-23)
  - Foundation Executives Group, 1983-1986 (Box 44, Folder 1-5)
  - Gannett Center for Media Studies, 1985-1986 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Sibyl and William T. Golden Foundation, 1984-1987 (Box 44, Folder 7-8)
  - Hampshire College Board of Overseers, 1980-1981 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Harvard Board of Overseers Committee to Visit the University Health Services, 1977-1982 (Box 44, Folder 9-14)
  - Hospital Research and Educational Trust, 1982-1986 (Box 44, Folder 15-17)
  - Independent Sector, Board of Directors, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 18-19)
  - Independent Sector, Board of Directors, 1983-1985 (Box 45, Folder 1-8)
  - Independent Sector, Committee on Public Information and Education, 1981-1984 (Box 45, Folder 9-10)
  - Independent Sector, Membership drive, 1981-1985 (Box 45, Folder 11-14)
  - Independent Sector, Statement by Margaret Mahoney on behalf of Independent Sector, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - The Jackson Laboratory, 1988-1990 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - John J. McCloy International Center, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Liasion Committee on Continuing Medication Education, 1976-1980 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 19-23)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1986-1990 (Box 46, Folder 1-11)
  - Marymount Manhattan College, President's Council, 1981-1982 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Corporation, 1984-1985 (Box 46, Folder 13-14)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Visiting Committee for the Medical Department, 1975-1982 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Institute of Medicine, 1977-1987 (Box 46, Folder 16-21)
  - National Board of Medical Examiners, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research Advisory Committee, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - National Council on Patient Information and Education, 1983-1984 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1978-1981 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - National Humanities Center, 1977-1982 (Box 47, Folder 5-7)
  - National Research Council: Board on Maternal, Child, and Family Health Research, 1978-1982 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, General, 1982-1998 (Box 47, Folder 9-11)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, Margaret Ellerbe Mahoney Symposium, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - New York City, Advisory Board of Office of Chief Medical Examiner, 1987-1988 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - New York City, Commission on the Year, 2000; 1986 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - New York City Major's Commission on Industrial and Commercial Incentive Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 47, Folder 16-19)
  - New York Hospital, Cornell Medical Center Advisory Board, 1982-1986 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - New York State, Bar Association's Council on Law and Society, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - New York State, Special Advisory Committee on Minority Recruitment and Retention in Medical Schools, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 22-23)
  - New York State, Non-Profit Coordination Committee, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1978-1983 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - James Picker Foundation, 1978-1985 (Box 47, Folder 26-27)
  - James Picker Foundation, 1978-1985 (Box 48, Folder 1-4)
  - Population Council, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Public Committee on Mental Health, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Salisbury Cathedral Spire Trust, 1987-1991 (Box 48, Folder 8-11)
  - Smith College Board of Trustees, 1988-1990 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Sun Valley Forum on National Health, Inc., 1974-1981 (Box 48, Folder 13-21)
  - Sun Valley Forum on National Health, Inc., 1982-1985 (Box 49, Folder 1-7)
  - Trinity Church, General, 1982-1995 (Box 49, Folder 8-16)
  - Trinity Church, Five Year Plan for Grants Program, 26 Sep 1983 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Trinity Church, Report on State of Hispanic Ministry in the Episcopal Church, 29 Jan 1985 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Committee on Ways and Means: Subcommittee on Health: Advisory Panel on National Health Insurance, 1975 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Congressional Office of Technology Assessment, Health Program Advisory Committee, 1981-1985 (Box 49, Folder 20-21)
  - U.S. Congressional Office of Technology Assessment, Health Program Advisory Committee, 1981-1985 (Box 50, Folder 1-5)
  - U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Medical Assistance Advisory Council, 1969-1971 (Box 50, Folder 7-11)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Task Force on Medicaid and Related Programs, 1969-1971 (Box 50, Folder 12-13)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Medallion, 1979-1980 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - U.S. President's Commission on Mental Health: Task Panel on the Role of the Arts in Mental Health, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Children and Youth, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - U.S. University of California Los Angeles School of Medicine Board of Visitors, 1983-1987 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - University of Chicago Pritzker School of Medicine National Council, 1986-1990 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Washington University School of Medicine National Council, 1987-1997 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Women's Global Film Project, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Social organizations, The Arts Clubs of Washington, 1947-1953 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Social organizations, The Century Association, 1988-1990 (Box 50, Folder 22-23)
  - Social organizations, The Century Association, 1990-2010 (Box 51, Folder 1-10)
  - Social organizations, The Cosmopolitan club, 1970-2006 (Box 51, Folder 11-16)
  - Social organizations, The Lotos Club, 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 17-18)
  - Social organizations, The Tennessee Society, 1976-1979 (Box 51, Folder 19)
- Photographs, 1925-2007; 5; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series is divided into four sub-series: Portraits of Margaret Mahoney, Scrapbook photographs, Professional photographs, and Other photographs.
  The first sub-series, Portraits of Margaret Mahoney, documents professional headshots, in addition to a smaller number of more artistic portraits of Margaret, from 1940-1998.